Tuan Mai. Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate receiving my Honours Bachelor of Computer Science (B.CS.) in 2019 from Sheridan College. With great experience as a mobile application developer and researcher with a strong passion for Engineering, whether it be software or hardware. Moreover, I also have a strong background in cross domain fields of health, as well as retail management. During the program, I experienced three co-op terms working as a mobile application developer, designing and developing an iOS application for the iPad that utilizes computer vision to detect distinct products from store shelves. Along with my work experience, the final year focused on my Undergraduate Thesis which was developing an augmented reality visualization system of polycystic kidney disease for preoperative planning.

Data Engineering has been a passion of mine and excites me as it allows me to explore data that can be used to help benefit society. Data engineering also solves some of the most complex problems, which I am enthusiastic about being a part of.

Skills

Proficient: Java, C#, OpenCV, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Python, C++, Swift, Android, JavaScript, Unity, HTML, MATLAB, Machine Learning, Docker, Spring

Framework

Familiar: Node.js, React, Assembly, Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Development Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_TuanMai

- Cluster Monitor: Developed a Cluster Monitoring Agent that allows users to monitor nodes in a cluster by storing each nodes' hardware specifications, as well as resource usages and store into a RDBMS Database in realtime. This project contains many bash scripts to automate the creation of SQL databases, generate tables, create|start|stop Docker, and run PostgreSQL queries.
- Core Java Apps: Developed three Java applications, all three applications implement Maven for build automation, as well as JUnit and Mockito for testing. The three applications built are:
 - GREP app replicates the recursive grep tool in a Linux based system. The grep application searches recursively
 in a given directory for a specified text pattern and outputs it to the user. This application uses Java I/O,
 regex, and stream APIs.
 - JDBC application a Java Database Connectivity application that connects to a PostgreSQL database using the Java-based data access technology. Following the DAO pattern, the user can do CRUD (create, read, update, delete) operations.
 - Twitter CLI Application an application to explore REST API by interacting with Twitter's API using HTTP GET/POST requests and responses to perform CRUD (create, read, update, delete) actions on tweets.
- SpringBoot App: In-progress
- Cloud & DevOps: Not started
- Hadoop: Not started Spark/Scala: Not started

Professional Experiences

Data Engineer, Jarvis, Toronto (2020-Present): Worked as a Junior Data Engineer in a small team collaborating to develop a series of product applications. Implemented three Java applications which utilized Maven, RDBMS, REST API, and Spring Framework. Testing done during development with JUnit and Mockito. Agile methodology is use in our team for collaboration and software development management. Daily Scrum meeting with the team to ensure everyone will meet deadlines and any issues would be resolved. Experience with WFH (working from home) and ability to collaborate with teammates effectively.

Mobile Application Developer, Encore Market Engagement, Oakville (2016-2018): Worked in a small team of 4 to design, prototype, and develop a solution for a current retail market management bottleneck. Worked as both a Mobile Application Developer and Team Lead to design an application to detect products of interest in retail stores. Designed and developed an iOS (Swift) application that uses machine learning and computer vision (OpenCV) to enhance sales representatives' routine.

Academic Researcher, Sheridan College, Oakville (2015-2015): Responsible for researching different wearable technology that could be incorporated into academia. Additionally, worked on integrating wearable devices to help aid and improve within academia by increasing proficiency of students and encourage learning.

Education & Academic Projects

Sheridan College (2014-2019), Honours Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science

- Undergraduate Thesis: Designed and developed a HoloLens augmented reality application (C#) that allows medical professionals to better plan surgical procedures, and enable real-time collaboration. The application reads in a patient's DICOM files (CTs, MRIs, US) then reconstructs the scanned organ in an interactive 3D model. This gives medical professionals more spatial information on the organ as well as a higher detail when viewing the organ in 3D versus referring to 2D images.
- Microsoft Imagine Cup: Team lead for a 3-person team competing in Microsoft's Imagine Cup, building an application to assist disabled citizens. The project revolved around exploring the usage of the Microsoft Band in order to control motorized wheelchairs with wrist/arm motion.

University of Ontario Institute of Technology (2012-2014), Honours Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical Engineering (Did not complete)

- Completed 60 Credits: Completed 60 credits towards Honours Bachelor of Electrical Engineering including courses such as: Electrical Engineering Fundamentals, Electronics, Circuit Analysis. Experience with lab equipment such as oscilloscopes.
- Mentored high school FIRST Robotics Team: Mentored high school's FIRST Robotics team, guiding them on design and implementation of hardware and software components.

Certificates & Awards & Activities

- Selected to showcase projects to:
 - Tim Cook (Apple CEO) Jan 23, 2016
 - Honourable Deb Matthews (Minister of Advanced Education and Skills Development) Jan 17, 2017
- Mobile Computer Symposium Competition First Place (Oct 25, 2016)